## Henrik Andersson

Contact

Citizenship: Swedish

Australian Permanent Resident Date of Birth: 8 February 1980

Home: (07) 3217 0331 Mobile: 0401 063 467 Email: alfhenrik@gmail.com Twitter: ahandersson

Linked In: <a href="http://lnkd.in/rENYm9">http://lnkd.in/rENYm9</a>
Blog: <a href="http://henri.kandersson.com">http://henri.kandersson.com</a>

# Key Skills

Proficient in a variety of programming languages, technologies and concepts

.NET, C#, VB.Net, ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC WPF, WCF, Entity Framework, Win Forms, Windows Phone 7, SVN, TFS, GIT MVVM, MVC, TDD

## Profile

I am an accomplished .NET Developer with a Bachelor of Information Technology in Software Engineering, specialising in Microsoft.NET technologies and practices.

I want to be part of the full life cycle of the software design process, from initial ideas through to the finished product. My key contributions to the development process would be in the technological planning and core development of the final product.

I am a self-starter, passionate about the technologies I work with, and driven to learn new technologies and enhancing my current skills, I am a team player that can work independently with minimal supervision, or as part of a bigger team and I am always is willing to help other team members. I have excellent interpersonal and communication skills both when it comes to technical staff and non-technical customers and I strive to achieve the best outcome for all parties involved.

## Education

Bachelor of Information Technology in Software Engineering Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, QLD

2003-2007

Diploma of Information Technology in Systems Administration Martin College, Brisbane, QLD

2002-2003

## Work Experience

#### Queensland Education, Training and Employment

Senior Technical Officer 1/2012 – present

Initiate and complete process of handing over the MyHR Recruitment application from project phase to being a supported application within the Application Support team and enhance the application with outstanding requirements from the project phase of the application.

- ✓ Develop solutions from Business Requirement documents
- ✓ Create support documentation as part of hand over from the Project team to the Application Support team
- ✓ Coordinate releases with the business and test team
- ✓ Develop fixes for TFS issues reported by the business and test team
- ✓ Liaise with other teams to integrate our application into the whole of government environment with regards to infrastructure, security and identity management

#### Flight Centre Limited

Senior Developer 12/2010 – 1/2012 Developer 5/2008 – 12/2010

Upgrade and enhance our robot ticketing system from .NET framework 1.1 to .NET framework 4.0. Upgrade Price Beat website from being a single page website to be a complete solution for all users

Implement functionality where our system calls a .NET user control from VB6, with the .NET user control then calling VB6.

- ✓ Upgrade our robot ticketing performance from .NET v1.1 to v2.0 by refactoring the code to make it use the new features of the, then, latest version of the .NET framework to make it more maintainable.
- ✓ Enhanced a web site where consultants can record customer's price beats to allow the full process that is involved with creating Price Beats by upgrading it from ASP.NET MVC1 to MVC3, using jQuery and AJAX.
- ✓ Created a user control in .NET that we added to a VB6 form so that we could use it to invoke required VB6 forms from the .NET user control by raising events that the VB6 form had attached to.

The System Works Group

Software Developer 12/2007 – 5/2008 2nd Level Support 8/2005 – 12/2007

Assisted in developing an Internet Banking solution for a customer that previously did not have an online banking site. Maintained and redesigned existing clients online banking solutions.

✓ Created an application that would communicate with the clients' core banking system to

- allow their customers to login to their online banking site and make transactions and other bank related tasks.
- ✓ Upgraded and redesigned clients online banking systems when we released a new version of our Internet Banking systems, or the client was rebranding their corporate and public web sites.

### Interests

#### Programming

In my spare time I enjoy dipping my toes in learning new technologies that I am not able to use at work due to restrictions on what technologies can be used in our applications. I have been working with WPF, MVC4, Windows Phone 7, and also been contributing to a few open source software projects.

Blog I have begun a blog where I want to document what I learn from using these new technologies to both benefit myself and also hopefully help others getting to learn something new and exciting.

Family I enjoy spending time with my wife and three children, if it is playing games, or riding bicycles, or going out for a day trip to the beach or the zoo.

## Languages

Native	Fluent	Scantly
Swedish	English	German, Spanish, Mandarin